<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Magnus Dahlgren - Scrum Master &amp; Agile team coach in London</title><author><name>Magnus Dahlgren</name></author><generator uri="https://github.com/magnusdahlgren/magnetizer">Magnetizer</generator><id>https://magnusd.cc/</id><updated>2019-09-23T00:00:02Z</updated><entry><title>Printable weather symbol cards for retrospectives - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/printable-weather-symbol-cards.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/printable-weather-symbol-cards.html</id><updated>2019-09-23T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>The sprint weather report is one of my favourites when it comes to agile check-in exercises for retrospectives. I used to run this exercise by printing each symbol on A4, put them up on the board and let people dot vote, but it always felt a bit wasteful to throw away the marked print outs at the en…</summary></entry><entry><title>10 check-in exercises for agile retrospectives - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/check-in-exercises-agile-retrospectives.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/check-in-exercises-agile-retrospectives.html</id><updated>2019-09-02T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>A quick check-in exercise is a great way to start a retrospective. Not only does it help the group get warmed up and quickly get a feeling for how everyone feels the sprint went. It’s also a really useful tool for you as the facilitator, as a way to assess what’s going on. Is whatever plan you have …</summary></entry><entry><title>Let’s do this! Again. - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/lets-do-this-again.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/lets-do-this-again.html</id><updated>2019-08-11T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>I used to blog quite a bit about Scrum and Agile a couple of years ago. My old blog is still there, in all its glory. But then I stopped. It wasn’t so much a conscious decision. Instead, it was just that the gap between posts grew. A week became a month, became a year, became two. Recently, I have s…</summary></entry></feed>