<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Magnus Dahlgren - Product Manager</title><author><name>Magnus Dahlgren</name></author><generator uri="https://github.com/magnusdahlgren/magnetizer">Magnetizer</generator><id>https://magnusd.cc/</id><updated>2020-01-27T00:00:02Z</updated><entry><title>My favourite online meeting tools? A sharpie and a pad of sticky notes - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/my-favourite-online-meeting-tools-sharpie-sticky-notes.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/my-favourite-online-meeting-tools-sharpie-sticky-notes.html</id><updated>2020-01-27T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>As much as we value individuals and interactions over tools in agile, there is no way around it: Proper tools are essential for good remote meetings. If an individual has a bad microphone, we can’t hear them. If they have a bad camera, we can’t see them. If they have a bad internet connection, we wi…</summary></entry><entry><title>12 remotely useful tips for those being part of a partially distributed team - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/remotely-useful-tips-for-partially-distributed-teams.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/remotely-useful-tips-for-partially-distributed-teams.html</id><updated>2020-01-16T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>There are many reasons why some teams are partially distributed, with some team members working together in an office and one or more others from somewhere else. Perhaps it hasn’t been possible to hire someone locally with the desired skills, or the team members just value the flexibility to work fr…</summary></entry><entry><title>Some of my older blog posts, republished - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/some-older-posts-republished.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/some-older-posts-republished.html</id><updated>2019-11-21T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Before starting this latest incarnation of my blog, I was blogging in a couple of different places. Judging from the traffic, some of those posts still seem valuable to people so I’ve decided to move them here. That way, they won’t disappear when I shut down my older sites. Rather than rewriting the…</summary></entry><entry><title>Do some target practice in your next retrospective - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/printable-shooting-target.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/printable-shooting-target.html</id><updated>2019-10-11T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>... and get your printable “shooting target” here Regardless of whether you use a print-out (for example using my template below :) or draw one on a whiteboard, a shooting target can be a simple but versatile tool for scoring pretty much anything in your retrospectives. Here are some examples of how…</summary></entry><entry><title>Why small Scrum teams rock - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/why-small-scrum-teams-rock.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/why-small-scrum-teams-rock.html</id><updated>2019-09-27T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>The more, the merrier, right? Well, not in Scrum. Every time I’ve been working with a team bigger than the 3-9 people guideline, I’ve experienced how incredibly hard it can be to make Scrum work well in these conditions. And problems can start showing even with teams towards the higher end of what’s…</summary></entry><entry><title>Printable weather symbol cards for retrospectives - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/printable-weather-symbol-cards.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/printable-weather-symbol-cards.html</id><updated>2019-09-23T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>The sprint weather report is one of my favourites when it comes to agile check-in exercises for retrospectives. I used to run this exercise by printing each symbol on A4, put them up on the board and let people dot vote, but it always felt a bit wasteful to throw away the marked print outs at the en…</summary></entry><entry><title>10 check-in exercises for agile retrospectives - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/check-in-exercises-agile-retrospectives.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/check-in-exercises-agile-retrospectives.html</id><updated>2019-09-02T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>A quick check-in exercise is a great way to start a retrospective. Not only does it help the group get warmed up and quickly get a feeling for how everyone feels the sprint went. It’s also a really useful tool for you as the facilitator, as a way to assess what’s going on. Is whatever plan you have …</summary></entry><entry><title>Processes and tools are not enemies of Agile - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/processes-and-tools-not-enemies-of-agile.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/processes-and-tools-not-enemies-of-agile.html</id><updated>2018-03-26T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Whenever a group of agilists meet, it seems to be only a matter of time before someone points out that “doing agile is not enough, we need to be agile”. Hard to argue with that! Agile practices alone will not make us agile. Simply going through the motions of “doing agile” won’t deliver the outcomes…</summary></entry><entry><title>Seven sins of a Scrum Master - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/seven-sins-of-a-scrum-master.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/seven-sins-of-a-scrum-master.html</id><updated>2017-06-22T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>The Scrum Master will never be responsible for the success of the product. However, they have an important role in helping those who are, the product owner and the team. A good Scrum Master can significantly increase the odds of success. Similarly, a bad Scrum Master can derail everything, causing d…</summary></entry><entry><title>Continuous improvement is what success as a Scrum Master is all about - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/continuous-improvement-success-scrum-master.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/continuous-improvement-success-scrum-master.html</id><updated>2017-06-06T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>As long as things improve, they get better On recent commutes, I have traded the tube for the bus. The quieter environment allows me to spend the time listening to podcasts and I have ended up listening to Vasco Duarte’s Scrum Master Toolbox podcast a lot. One of my favourite questions he asks his g…</summary></entry><entry><title>5 situations when Scrum may not be your best choice - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/5-situations-scrum-may-not-best-choice.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/5-situations-scrum-may-not-best-choice.html</id><updated>2017-06-08T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Not every story about Scrum is a success story. Scrum can fail. One of the reasons why many teams don’t get the value out of Scrum they were hoping is that they are trying to use it in a situation or environment where it is not appropriate. No set of practices will work in every single context and S…</summary></entry><entry><title>#noestimates is just story points done right - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/noestimates-just-story-points-done-right.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/noestimates-just-story-points-done-right.html</id><updated>2017-03-23T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Estimation has long been a natural part of software development. Therefore, an approach like #noestimates, which gets rid of estimation can seem quite suspicious. After all, there are good reasons why we estimate. We need to know how long something will take so that we can decide whether it’s worth …</summary></entry><entry><title>A better name for Scrum Master? - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/better-name-for-scrum-master.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/better-name-for-scrum-master.html</id><updated>2018-03-11T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Does it matter what we call the Scrum Master role? Not really. The role titles are just words. What matters is the work a person does. However, I have come to realise that in some cases, classifying myself as a Scrum Master may actually limit my chances of fully meeting the potential of the role. Le…</summary></entry><entry><title>7 reasons some user stories aren’t useful stories - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/7-reasons-why-some-stories-arent-useful-stories.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/7-reasons-why-some-stories-arent-useful-stories.html</id><updated>2017-03-01T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Simply writing a sentence on the format “As a x, I want to y, so that z” won’t make it a user story. There is a lot more to stories than this. In this article, I will take a look at what some common pitfalls are. 1. Stories that don’t deliver value on their own The goal of any agile process is to de…</summary></entry><entry><title>Is your daily stand-up a daily waste of time? - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/is-your-daily-stand-up-daily-waste-of-time.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/is-your-daily-stand-up-daily-waste-of-time.html</id><updated>2017-01-16T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>These 5 experiments may help We’ve probably all been there at some point, standing in a daily stand-up meeting, thinking “This is a complete waste of my time!”. Maybe, the stand-up dragged on forever, with someone going on and on about the day before in such detail that you start wondering whether t…</summary></entry><entry><title>Self-selecting teams on a small scale - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/self-selecting-teams-on-a-small-scale.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/self-selecting-teams-on-a-small-scale.html</id><updated>2016-07-11T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>You don’t need a lot of people for self-selection to be useful. Self-selection is a practice where people get to choose for themselves which team they want to be in. Typically, it is associated with large scale agile implementations and obviously, it does make sense to tackle the complicated task of…</summary></entry><entry><title>5 things I’ve learned about Scrum the hard way - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/5-things-ive-learned-about-scrum-the-hard-way.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/5-things-ive-learned-about-scrum-the-hard-way.html</id><updated>2016-05-16T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>I got my Scrum Master certification in 2007 and have been using Scrum in many of the teams I’ve been working in since then. It’s fair to say it’s been an educational journey and in this article, I’d like to mention a few things I’ve found out along the way. 1. Scrum really does work best for small t…</summary></entry><entry><title>A quick way to estimate a whole product backlog - Magnus Dahlgren</title><link href="https://magnusd.cc/quick-way-to-estimate-whole-backlog.html"/><id>https://magnusd.cc/quick-way-to-estimate-whole-backlog.html</id><updated>2016-02-03T00:00:01Z</updated><summary>Early on, when starting a new project, we will have a product backlog (or the starting point of one) but without estimates. To be able to create a first release plan, burn down chart and so on, we will want to get at least rough estimates for all these items. If using planning poker, we will end up …</summary></entry></feed>